Hey, welcome! Have you ever wanted to turn a yes into a no in English but got a little stuck?
こんにちは！英語で「はい」を「いいえ」に変えたいと思ったことはありませんか？
Well, today we're going to tackle exactly that. Making negative sentences.
今日はそのことに取り組みます。否定文の作り方です。
And I promise you, it is so much easier than you think. Let's dive in.
思っているよりずっと簡単です。さあ、始めましょう。
So, think about it. It's easy to say, I am hungry. But what if you're not?
考えてみてください。「お腹が空いている」と言うのは簡単ですが、そうでない場合はどうしますか？
How do you say that you don't want another slice of cake? It seems like a small thing,
もう一切れケーキが欲しくないと言うにはどうすればいいのでしょう？小さなことのようですが、
but getting this right is absolutely essential for everyday conversations.
これを正しく言えることは日常会話において非常に重要です。
And right here, you can see the difference crystal clear.
ここで、違いがはっきり見えます。
On the one hand, I am hungry is like saying I equals hungry.
I am hungry.る」は「私=お腹が空いている」と同じです。
But look at the other side, I am not hungry.
でも、反対側を見てみましょう。「お腹が空いていない」。
Now it means I does not equal hungry.
今度は「私は≠お腹が空いている」という意味になります。
The whole meaning just flips all because of one tiny, tiny change.
意味が一変するのは、ほんの小さな変化のおかげです。
So what's the secret?
では、秘密は何でしょう？
Well, it really all comes down to a single super powerful word.
実は、非常に強力な単語に集約されます。
This one little word is the key that's going to unlock
この小さな単語が、
Pretty much every negative sentence you need when you're using the verb to be.
「be動詞」を使う際のほとんどすべての否定文を作る鍵です。
And there it is. The magic word is simply not. Yep, that's it.
それがこちらです。魔法の言葉は「not」です。はい、それだけです。
This small word does all the heavy lifting for us.
この小さな言葉が私たちの助けになります。
It's the secret ingredient we've been looking for.
私たちが探していた秘密のことばです。
So now let's take that magic word and turn it into a simple,
では、この魔法の言葉を使って、シンプルで
solid rule that you can count on every single time you use verbs like am,
確実なルールにしましょう。動詞am、is、areを使うとき、いつでも使えます。
is, and are. And check this out, it's just three super simple steps.
これを見てください。たった3つの簡単なステップです。
First, you spot the B verb.
まず、be動詞を見つけます。
Second, you just drop the word not right after it.
次に、その後にnotを付けます。
And third, well, there is no third step. That's it, you're done.
そして、三つ目はありません。それで終わりです。
Your sentence is officially negative. It really is that easy.
あなたの文は正式に否定文になりました。本当にそれだけ簡単です。
Let's see this in action, okay? So you have you are from Canada.
では、実際に見てみましょう。例えば、「あなたはカナダ出身です」。
We find our verb, are. We put not right after it and bam,
動詞areを見つけて、その後にnotを付けると、はい、
you are not from Canada, perfect. What about for the verb is?
「あなたはカナダ出身ではありません」となります。完璧です。次はisの場合はどうでしょう？
Any different? Nope, it's the exact same logic.
違いはありますか？いいえ、全く同じ論理です。
she is a student becomes she is not a student.
「彼女は学生です」は「彼女は学生ではありません」になります。
The pattern just works every single time. You can rely on it.
このパターンは毎回機能します。信頼できます。
Let's do just one more to really lock it in.
もう一つやってみましょう。
What if it's plural, like they are busy?
もし「彼らは忙しい」と言ったら？
Well, it transforms into you already know it, they are not busy.
「彼らは忙しくない」となります。
One rule to cover them all.
一つのルールがすべての場合にあてはまります。
Okay, so you've totally got the basic rule down.
さて、基本ルールはしっかり理解できましたね。
Now, if you wanna take it to the next level
次のステップに進みましょう
and sound way more natural and fluent,
もっと自然で流暢に聞こえるように、
You know, like you hear in movies and songs,
映画や歌で聞くように、
we need to talk about a little pro tip, contractions.
短縮形形について話しましょう。
So what in the world is a contraction? It's really simple.
短縮形とは何でしょう？とてもシンプルです。
It's just a shorter, faster, and much more common way
二つの単語を一つにまとめて、短く、早く、より一般的に言う方法です。
of saying two words by kind of squishing them together into one.
ここが本当に面白いところです。
Now this is where it gets really cool.
選択肢が複数あります。例えば、「あなたは忙しくない」は、
You often have more than one option. For example, you are not busy
二つの異なる方法で短縮できます。「you're not busy」または「you aren't busy」と言えます。
can be shortened in two different ways. You can say you're not busy
そして、どちらも完全に正しく、よく使われます。
or you can say you aren't busy.
この二つの選択肢は、実は二つの異なるパターンから来ています。最初のパターンでは、
And guess what? They're both totally correct and used all the time.
主語と動詞を組み合わせるので、「she's not」となります。
These two options actually come from two different patterns. In the first one,
二つ目のパターンでは、動詞と「not」を組み合わせるので、「she isn't」となります。
you combine the subject and the verb, so you get something like she's not.
でも、覚えておくべき非常に重要な例外があります。
In the second one, you combine the verb and the word not, which gives you she isn't.
ほとんどのものは二つの選択肢がありますが、I am notだけは一つの縮約形しかありません。
But wait, there's one really, really important exception you've got to remember.
I'm notです。この点には注意してください。I amn'tは
While almost everything else gives you two choices, I am not only has one contraction.
標準的な英語では使われません。さて、これで十分です。ルールは理解できましたね。
I'm not. Please be careful with this one because I am and is a super common mistake,
さあ、あなたの素晴らしい新しいスキルを試してみませんか？
but it's just not used in standard English. All right, that's enough talk. You've got the rules,
準備はいいですか？では、最初のチャレンジです。
you've got the pro tips. How about we put your awesome new skills to the test right now? You
この文を否定文にするにはどうしますか？
ready? Okay, here's your first challenge. How would you make this sentence negative?
「部屋はきれいです」。少し考えてみてください。どうなりますか？
The room is clean. Go ahead, take a second and think about it. What are all the different
時間切れです。The room is not clean.と言うか、
ways you could say it. And times up. Here are your answers. You could say the full version,
短縮形を使ってThe room's not clean.と言えます。
or the room isn't clean. If you got all three of those, you are doing an amazing job.
The room isn't clean.でもいいですね。 この3つはどれもOKです。
Let's keep this ball rolling. Ready for the next one? Here it is.
さあ、次に進みましょう。準備はいいですか？ こちらです。
You are busy. How do you flip that one into a negative? Again, think about all the possible
They are busy.それをどうやって 否定形に変えますか？考えてみてください。
ways to say it. And the answers are, you are not busy, you are not busy, and you aren't busy.
言い方はいろいろ。They are not, They're not, They aren't
See, you are totally getting the hang of this. It's all just following that same simple pattern.
ほら、すっかりコツがつかめましたね。 同じシンプルなパターンに従っているだけです。
Okay, let's wrap this all up nice and neat. We're going to put everything we just learned
さて、これをきれいにまとめましょう。 今学んだことをすべて 00:04:32,640一覧表参照シートにまとめます。
look back on whenever you want. And here it is. This table has got it all. On the left,
こちらです。この表にはすべてが含まれています。左側には
you've got the full form. In the middle, you see the first contraction pattern. And on the right,
完全な形があります。真ん中には最初の短縮形パターンがあり、右側には
the second one. Just look. Everything has two options except for our one special case. I am not.
2つ目があります。見てください。特別なケース「I am not」を除いて、 すべてに2つの選択肢があります。
It only has one. This is your master key right here. So look, if you only remember one single
I am notの短縮形1つしかありません。これポイントです。 さて、一つだけ覚えておいてほしいことがあります。
thing from our chat today, please let it be this. To make a B verb negative, all you ever have to
動詞を否定形にするには、 その後にnotを加えるだけです。それだけです。
do is just add not right after it. That's the foundation. Everything else we talked about
いろいろお話しましたが、 すべてこのシンプルなアイデアの上に成り立っています。
just builds on top of that simple, simple idea.
さあ、あなたは英語の文法の 大きな部分をマスターしました。
And just like that, you've mastered a huge piece of English grammar.
問題を取り上げ、シンプルなルールを学び、 自信を持って使えるスキルを手に入れました。
You took a problem, learned a simple rule, and now you have the skills to use it with confidence.
英語をきちと理解できることが わかりましたね。
You've proved that any part of English can be broken down and understood.
では、次に何をマスターしましょうか？